Hello and welcome back.
Now let's take a look at the hardware and software used in the course.
If you're not already aware of the ESB 32 by now, I'll just mentioned that the ESB 32 is a series of
low cost, low power SLC or system on a CHIP series of microcontrollers with integrated Wi-Fi and dual
mode Bluetooth.
And for this course, we'll use an ESP 32 depth kit.
Any ESP 32 dev kit will work for this course and I personally have a few decades.
However, I do prefer working with the rubber dev kit.
You can find information about it if you follow this link and you can find information about all the
SPECIF dev kits via the following link.
Other hardware components include an arguably either the package type here or the common NATO.
A common cathode type also will use an AM to 302 DHT 22 sensor for temperature and humidity data.
And you'll also want to have jumper wires and a breadboard available to connect these components to
the ESP 32 dev kit.
So moving on to the software requirements, we'll use the Eclipse RDF plugin which is available for
Linux, Mac and Windows and I'll demonstrate the Windows installation.
However, in the documentation they provide, you'll find instructions for both Linux and Mac as well.
The Windows installation is an all in one install and gives you the ESPN PDF Idea of tools and Eclipse
as well.
You can also install it as a plug in to an existing Eclipse installation if you prefer.
It's quite easy to do and you can find details here.
With the eclipse idea, you can easily create, see, make ideas projects, create launch targets for
different variants of the ESP, compile, flash and debug as well as view the serial output, which
will be our main method of debugging in this course.
Okay.
So next we'll take a look at the core structure.